Bilguun Bayarsaikhan

SOFTWARE ENGINEED

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia

 \square (+976) 8002-6446 | \square biligunb@gmail.com | \P biligunb.ml | \square biligunb | \square Bilguun

Summary

Passionate Software Engineer with **5** years of experience. I started out my career writing JUnit tests and Integration tests using Selenium, which is why I believe **quality code** comes from writing good tests. For the last 3 years I've been developing products with NodeJS Frameworks, taking part in every step of the way including **designing** from scratch to **testing** features and **deploying** on the cloud.

I love taking on challenges and **documenting** the solution thorough when it's done, so that the others won't have hard time with it. As a hobby I learn about new technologies, try them and write a blog on **Medium**. Also I contribute to growing **Machine Learning UB** (MLUB) community.

Programming & Frameworks JavaScript/TypeScript, Python, Java, React.js, React Native

Tools & Technologies Docker, Selenium, Puppeteer, JMeter, GitLab CI/CD, Jenkins CI, Jest, Mocha

Cloud Providers Certified AWS Solutions Architect Professional, MS Azure Fundamentals, OCI Architect Associate

Work Experience_

Senior Software Engineer

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia

Unimedia Solutions LLC - A subsidiary of Japanese Unimedia Group

Feb. 2019 - PRESENT

- Currently developing products on top of **Blockchain Platform** and serving as a deputy team lead (Web & Mobile & Browser extension)
- Introduced Continuous Deployment on multiple projects using GitLab CI/CD saving 100+ hours monthly
- Led a team of 3 to improve blockchain transaction speed from 150/tps to +1500/tps (10x) by refactoring old code & architecting infrastructure
- Architectured, deployed and maintained cloud infrastructure using CloudFormation & Docker on AWS
- Mentors new team members, prepares and instructs colleagues on technical subjects (AWS, Hyperledger, Testing etc...)

Software Engineer Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia

UNIMEDIA SOLUTIONS LLC - A SUBSIDIARY OF JAPANESE UNIMEDIA GROUP

April.2017 - Feb. 2019

- In an Agile team, worked as a full-stack engineer heavily focused on back-end. (Springboot, RoR, Loopback)
- Integrated Selenium WebDriver and wrote scenario test cases for multiple browsers with a +90% code coverage
- Implemented Page Object Model (POM) that improved test runtime significantly and shared knowledge with benkyokais
- Improved existing codebase while refactoring using coding principles, linter (ESLint), pair-programming and MR reviews

Project Manager

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia

Sep.2016 - April.2017

INTERACTIVE BI LLC - 1 OF THE BIGGEST SOFTWARE COMPANY IN MONGOLIAN PRIVATE SECTOR

- Supervised a team of 5 to complete Health Information System (HIS) for government hospital
 Negotiated with customers on system design and budget allocation. Administered Waterfall model on feature implementation
- · Handled coordination of Development team, Marketing team and IT support team to make sure project is on **schedule**

Education

Eskisehir Osmangazi University

Eskisehir, Turkey

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sep. 2011 - Jul. 2016

• CS Fundamentals (Computer Architecture, Networks, OS, Micro-computer), Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Mobile programming

Projects, Publications & Courses

Serverless web on AWS biligunb.ml

BUILT PERSONAL PORTFOLIO WEB FOR A MONTHLY COST OF 0.5\$ (UP TO 2 MILLION REQUESTS)

Dec. 2020

- Uses S3 & CloudFront for static web hosting. API Gateway, Lambda & SNS are utilized to have serverless backend
- GitHub actions and Data pipeline works together to enable **continuous deployment**

Open Source - COVID Tracing Mongolia

CTM-19

CONTRIBUTED TO DEVELOPING AND TESTING CONTACT TRACING APP

Nov. 2020

- Researched Exposure Notification API, prepared Mongolian documentation, translated usage guides and wrote a **blog**
- · Created test cases, built and tested on mobile app on how the app works and shared it to government officials

AWS:101 online course uschool.mn

AUTHORED AND CURATED 12 HOURS LESSONS

Aug. 2020

• Designed to help developers that are new to AWS and cloud computing with Theoretical knowledge with **hands-on labs**

SEPTEMBER 12, 2021 BILGUUN.B · RÉSUMÉ